(technological whirring)
(shorts out)
- [Man] So we're able to spawn
our enemy using code now,
and we can set it to whatever
positions that we want.
But we're gonna make it a
little more random than just
manually putting in a
position to spawn at.
So we're actually going to
use the "random" class again
to generate random numbers
that the enemies will spawn at.
So in our Start method is where we're
going to create these random positions,
so we'll use a float,
and we need a spawn position.
Now, keep in mind in our
game we have a certain range
that we want to work
in for the X and the Z.
So, on the Z, if we just use
our SpawnManager for example.
So probably about up to there,
so around like nine on the Z,
so negative nine or so on the other side,
and then on the X
you want to make sure that it's even,
so we could probably keep it
negative nine and nine as well.
So, for our spawn position
we'll both need an X.
Okay, so you want to
change the range at all
and we'll make it be a random range.
And the minimum value
that we want is gonna be negative nine,
and we're going to use
a maximum value of nine.
And then same thing for our Z position.
So a Float, spawn position of Z,
get a random range,
and we'll say negative nine
and nine for that for now.
And then in our Instantiate method,
so we can change this new vector3
we'll make it a spawn position
X, and a spawn position Z.
Now if we wanted to clean this up
even just a little bit more,
so we can just make a new vector3,
we'll make this the
actual random position,
and then we can actually just
take out this entire line,
we'll paste it,
and then where that new Vector 3 was
we can just call this "random position".
So now this line is very readable,
we're instantiating our enemy
prefab at a random position
using the rotation that it's set at,
and then we calculate that
random position above it.
Last but not least,
now we do have a few
more hard-coded values
so we'll clean that up
just a little bit more,
just to make our code
as readable as possible.
So we're going to make a
private variable this time
of float and we'll call
this the "spawnRange"
and we'll make that nine
so then that way we're always
keeping it within that square
so that way we don't
accidentally spawn an enemy
outside of the octagon shape that we have.
We'll go into our Random Range,
just change this to spawnRange.
One thing to note, this
is a bit redundant.
We could easy just make
it a spawn position
but if we ever wanted to change the Z,
at least now we have the option,
so, it just makes things
a little bit easier.
Now when we save and we go into Unity
and we play our game,
you should see a ball
spawns in a random
position and then we stop.
If we try again, different position
and then one more time for good measure,
and there you go! Awesome!
So what you're gonna do is in
your SpawnManager class,
you can create your own
private float variable for the spawnRange
and our start class we're just
going to clean up our code a lot
and make it so that our enemies
spawn at a random position.
So, using a X-position
variable for the spawn
we'll set it to a random
range within our spawnRange,
between the negative and
the positive position.
Same thing with the Z, to a
negative and positive position,
somewhere within a random range.
We're going to create a new
vector3 to hold our position,
and that's where we're going to change out
the hard-coded values
to be our spawn position
for the X and the Z and then
in our Instantiate method
we can just take out that entire vector3
and then just make that one whole variable
so then this line of code is
an incredibly easy to read.
Now it's your turn!
(technological whirring)